Preliminary Guide to the William Volker Fund Records, 1953-1961
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
William Volker Fund records 1953-1961
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
William Volker Fund
1.8 linear feet Extent: 25 Items
The William Volker Fund operated from 1932-1965 as a charitable foundation promoting free-market and liberatarian economics. Along with funding research, the Fund sponsored the work of Old Right economists, and gave liberatarian books to college libraries through the National Book Foundation. Accession (2009-0179) (25 items; 1.8 lin. ft.; dated 1953-1961) includes reports and surveys commissioned by the Fund regarding education and health; sourcebooks on education resources and conferences; National Book Foundation files; and other miscellaneous materials, including a William Volker Fund office manual and board meeting reports.
RL.02044
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The William Volker Fund Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Historical Note
The William Volker Fund operated from 1932-1965 as a charitable foundation promoting free-market and liberatarian economics. Along with funding research, the Fund sponsored the work of Old Right economists, and gave liberatarian books to college libraries through the National Book Foundation.
Collection Overview
Accession (2009-0179) (25 items; 1.8 lin. ft.; dated 1953-1961) includes reports and surveys commissioned by the Fund regarding education and health; sourcebooks on education resources and conferences; National Book Foundation files; and other miscellaneous materials, including a William Volker Fund office manual and board meeting reports.
Collection Arrangement
This collection has not been processed; materials have been reboxed but no arrangement has been conducted at this time.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Templeton, Kenneth S.; William Volker Fund; National Book Foundation (U.S.); Economics; Education; Economic development -- Effect of education on; Health; United States -- Economics
Contents of Collection
- Accession (2009-0179), 1953-1961, (3 boxes)
  Accession (2009-0179) (25 items; 1.8 lin. ft.; dated 1953-1961) includes reports and surveys commissioned by the Fund regarding education and health; sourcebooks on education resources and conferences; National Book Foundation files; and other miscellaneous materials, including a William Volker Fund office manual and board meeting reports.
  - Manual of Office Procedure (Box 1)
  - Association for Christian Schools: Schools Weighed in the Balance, 1961
  - Five-year Survey of Education, Report II, Spring 1960 (2 copies)
  - A Study of College Libraries, May 1953
  - Symposium on Individuality, Final Report, Fall 1957
  - Education Conferences and Symposia, report and request, 1960
  - Report on Education Conferences and Symposia, Fall 1961
  - A Source Book on Summer Education, 1956
  - National Book Foundation, 1960
  - Health and welfare director memos (Box 2)
  - Education director memos
  - Miscellaneous pages (2 folders)
  - Research & Writing and Book Publication & Distribution Projects
  - Discussion Guide for Summer Conference Planning, 1956 (2 copies)
  - Review and Recommendations, 1954
  - Review and Recommendations, 1956
  - William Volker Fund board meeting, Sept. 1961
  - Director's meeting: Survey of Education, Aug. 1954 (Box 3)
  - Private School Development Program, First Interim Report, Fall 1961
  - Private School Development Program, General Report, Fall 1960
  - Private School Development Program, Second General Report, Spring 1961
  - President's Report to the Directors, Fall 1961
  - Survey of Pre-College Education, 1960
  - A Source Book on Education Conferences, 1958-1959 (2 folders)
  - Report on the Conference on Parish and Church-Related Schools, Oct. 1960